Mary Ann Lewis papers
Litchfield Historical Society
Mary Ann Lewis papers
1811-1895
Litchfield Historical Society 7 South Street, P.O. Box 385 Litchfield, CT, 6759 URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org Phone: 860-567-4501 Fax: 860-567-3565
Lewis, Mary Ann R., 1797-1884; Phelps, Mary Lewis, 1836-1911
0.83
The Luke Lewis family moved to Litchfield, Conn. in 1811 and lived in a house at #7 East Street in the center of town. Mr. Luke Lewis operated a store on the property and his four daughters all attended the Litchfield Female Academy at various times from 1812-1821. The majority of the collection consists of invitations and replies from members of Litchfield families, Litchfield Female Academy students, and Litchfield Law School students.
1913-30-0
Biographical Note
Mary Ann R. Lewis was born February 1, 1797, the daughter of Luke and Mary H. (Root) Lewis. She and her three sisters, Amelia, Jane, and Louisa, all attended the Litchfield Female Academy. She died unmarried on June 7, 1884 and is buried in Litchfield's East Cemetery.
Scope and Contents
The Luke Lewis family moved to Litchfield, Conn. in 1811 and lived in a house at #7 East Street in the center of town. Mr. Luke Lewis operated a store on the property and his four daughters all attended the Litchfield Female Academy at various times from 1812-1821. The majority of the collection consists of invitations and replies from members of Litchfield families, Litchfield Female Academy students, and Litchfield Law School students.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is arranged in two series:
Series 1: Invitations
Series 2: Miscellaneous
Related Materials
In the Litchfield Female Academy Collection: Louisa (Lewis) Phelps' Autograph album (1817); Jane R. Lewis' Journal for the summer of 1820 and Autograph album circa 1820.
Information about related materials is available at http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Invitations
Topical Term:
Litchfield (Conn.) - Social life and customs
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Other Information
This collection was processed with support from the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Invitations
  This series is arranged alphabetically and consists of invitations sent to Lewis family members and replies to invitations sent by the Lewises. Most of the notes are undated or lack the year they were sent. As the majority of the items are invitations sent to Lewis family members or replies received by the Lewises from invitees to their invitations, some dates may be established. For example, notes sent to "the Misses Lewis" are presumed to be before 1830 because Amelia Lewis died in 1820, Jane Lewis died in 1830, and Louisa Lewis married in 1829, leaving only Mary Ann as a remaining Miss Lewis.
  Many of the invitations were sent by students of the Litchfield Law School or the Litchfield Female Academy. If the student can be identified, the dates of his/her attendance at the school are noted in the folder description.
  - Abbe, Dr. and Mrs. (Folder 1)
    Invitation to Mrs. and Mrs. Lewis and the young ladies for tea. Dated Jan. 14 [before 1830]
  - Abigail (Folder 2)
    Note to Betsey and Jane Lewis requesting they write in her book. [before 1830]
  - Attwater, Miss (Folder 3)
    To Miss Lewis, regrets that she cannot accept invitation.
  - Bacon, Francis, Mrs. (Folder 4)
    Invitation to Miss Lewis.
  - Beach, Mr. and Mrs. (Folder 5)
    To Mary Ann Lewis. Invitation to tea
  - Beecher, Miss (Folder 6)
    Invitation for tea to the Miss Lewises. [before 1830]
  - Beers, Mrs. (Folder 7)
    Mrs. Beers and Miss Gracie accept the invitation for tea from Mrs. and the Miss Lewises. [before 1830]
  - Boardman, Mr. (Folder 8)
    To Miss Lewis -Regrets he will be out of town and cannot accept invitation.
  - Bolkcom, Everitt, 1818 Jul 14 (Folder 9)
    Accepts invitation of Miss Lewis. Dated Wed. 14 July. [1818]
    Everett Bolkcom was a Litchfield Law Student in 1818.
  - Brace, John Pierce, and Brace, Lucy Porter (Folder 10)
    Two invitations for tea: one to Miss Lewis, dated Feb. 16, and one to the Misses Lewis dated August 23. Also to the Misses Lewis, regrets that they cannot accept the invitation. [before 1830]
  - Buel, Miss (Folder 11)
    Invitation for tea to Mises M. & A. Lewis. Dated March 10. [before 1820]
  - Buel, Miss (Folder 12)
    Invitation for tea to the Misses Lewis.
  - Buel, Misses (Folder 13)
    Three invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. One is dated Aug. 11. and one is Sept. 24th. [before 1830]
  - Bunker, Charles, 1822 Jan 14 (Folder 14)
    To the Misses Lewis, regrets that he cannot accept their invitation for that evening. Signed C. Bunker. Dated Jan. 14. Charles Bunker was a Litchfield Law School student in 1822.
  - Burgess, Mr. (Folder 15)
    To Misses Lewis. Accepts invitation for the next evening. [before 1830]
  - Butler, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 16)
    Two invitations for tea to Miss M. Lewis. One is dated March 9th for that evening.
  - Butler, Mrs. (Folder 17)
    To Miss Lewis - regrets she cannot accept invitation due to being out of town.
  - Carroll, Mr. (Folder 18)
    To Miss Lewis - regrets he cannot accept invitation.
  - Castor, Mr. (Folder 19)
    To Misses Lewis - accepts invitation for tea that evening, Jan. 26. [before 1830]
    Dyre Castor was a Litchfield Law School student in 1825.
  - Catlin, Flora (Folder 20)
    2 notes to Miss Lewis: one asking for the return of a book, and one requesting her friend's company if she is not attending the cotillion party that evening.
  - Catlin, Flora (Folder 21)
    2 invitations to the Misses Lewis - an invitation for tea; and requesting their company on the ride to a party. [before 1830]
  - Catlin, Misses (Folder 22)
    Four invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. One is dated Aug. 1818.
  - Catlin, Misses (Folder 23)
    To Miss Lewis - regrets that cannot accept invitation due to the arrival of some friends that evening.
  - Catlin, Miss (Folder 24)
    To Mary Ann Lewis - asks Mary Ann to lend her a book "Children of the Abbey".
  - Catlin, Dr. and Mrs. (Folder 25)
    Invitation to the Miss Lewises. Dated Tuesday April 24th [before 1830]
  - Clark, R. P. (Folder 26)
    3 invitations to Miss Jane Lewis. [before 1830].
    Roxana Clark Bolles [Roxana Phelps Clark] was a Litchfield Academy student in 1818-1819.
  - Clark, William M (Folder 27)
    To the Misses Lewis - accepts invitation for that evening (Wed.) [before 1830]
  - Collins, Misses (Folder 28)
    To Miss Lewis - Miss A. Collins accepts invitation for that evening and Miss M. Collins regrets she is unable to accept invitation due to her cousin Miss Farnham visiting. Dated Wed. July 14.
  - Collins, Misses (Folder 29)
    The Misses Collins invite the Misses Lewis for tea that evening. Dated Wed., Oct. 11. [before 1830]
  - Cooke, M., Miss (Folder 30)
    To Misses Lewis - regrets that she cannot accept invitation to tea that evening due to a cold. [before 1830]
  - Cooke, Roger W (Folder 31)
    Three notes - one to Miss Lewis - accepts invitation. One to the Misses Lewis - accepts invitation, dated Wed. July 14. One to Mary Ann Lewis postponing a ride due to a storm, dated Fri. March 13. [before 1830]
    Roger W. Cooke was a Litchfield Law School student in 1817.
  - Cowles, C. P., 1832 Jan 25 (Folder 32)
    Invites Mary Ann Lewis and Mary L. Root to tea that afternoon. Dated Jan. 25, 1832.
  - Darling, C., Miss (Folder 33)
    Invites Miss Jane Lewis to tea that evening. [before 1830]
    Clarinda Ely Darling was a Litchfield Female Academy student in 1818-1820.
  - Deming, Mr. (Folder 34)
    Accepts invitation of Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Deming, C., Mr., 1817 Jul 14 (Folder 35)
    To Miss Lewis - regrets he cannot accept invitation for tea that evening.
  - Deming, Mary (Folder 36)
    Two notes: accepts invitation of Miss Lewis for that evening; and, invites the Misses Lewis to tea.
  - Deming, Mary (Folder 37)
    Notes to Mary Ann Lewis: to Mariann not to worry about the lost die as they have a spare one in the house; asks for 2nd volume of "Camilla" if she has finished; reminds Mary Ann that she is visiting her that afternoon
  - Deming, Misses (Folder 38)
    To the Misses Lewis - 5 invitations to tea.
    To Miss Lewis - Miss Mary Deming regrets she cannot accept invitation and Miss Lucretia Deming accepts invitation for that evening. Dated Wed. July 14.
  - Deveaux, T., Miss (Folder 39)
    Invites Miss M.A. Lewis to a dance that evening.
    Theodosia Deveaux was a Litchfield Female Academy student in 1814-1816.
  - Devereux, Mr. (Folder 40)
    Regrets he cannot accept Miss Lewis' invitation beause he is leaving town.
  - E., Ann (Folder 41)
    To Mary Ann Lewis regrets that her parents cannot accept invitation but she will visit.
  - Farnham, L., Miss (Folder 42)
    Invites Maryann Lewis to attend school recitation.
    Laura Farnham was a Litchfield Female Academy student in 1815-1816 & 1819.
  - Glover, S, 1821 Dec 11 (Folder 43)
    S. Glover, J. DeLaMotta, & L. Harvey, managers invite Miss Jane Lewis to Mr. Dunning's assembly room.
    Samuel Glover was a Litchfield Law School student in 1820; Jacob Delamotta was there in 1821; and Leroy Harvey in 1821.
  - Glover, S, 1821 Dec 11 (Folder 44)
    S. Glover, J. DeLaMotta, & L. Harvey, managers invite Miss Mary Ann Lewis to Mr. Dunning's assembly room.
    Samuel Glover was a Litchfield Law School student in 1820-1821; Jacob Delamotta was there in 1821; and Leroy Harvey in 1821
  - Goodwin, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 45)
    Invitation for tea that evening to Miss M.A. Lewis. Dated Thursday March 29.
  - Gould, Edward S (Folder 46)
    Accepts invitation of Miss J. Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Gould, J.R., Mr. (Folder 47)
    To the Misses Lewis, regrets he cannot accept invitation due to health. [before 1830]
  - Gould, Miss (Folder 48)
    Invitation for tea to the Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Grant, Mr. (Folder 49)
    Regrets he cannot accept the invitation of the Misses Lewis due to health. [before 1830]
  - Head, Mrs. (Folder 50)
    Invitation for tea to Miss Lewis. Dated Tues. July 18.
  - Henry, G (Folder 51)
    Invitation to the Misses Lewis to attend the First Quarter Exhibition by scholars. [before 1830]
  - Henry, G (Folder 52)
    Printed invitation to Miss Jane Lewis for her attendance at the second quarter exhibition by scholars. [before 1830]
  - Holmes, Mr. (Folder 53)
    Regrets that he cannot accept the Misses Lewis invitation to tea due to being out of town. [before 1830]
  - Jones, Mr. (Folder 54)
    Regrets that he cannot accept Miss Lewis invitation for that evening due to a previous engagement.
  - Kerr, Mr. (Folder 55)
    Regrets that he cannot accept the invitation of Miss Lewis due to ill health. Dated Wed. July 14.
  - Kilbourn, Mr. (Folder 56)
    4 notes to the Misses Lewis; accepts invitation for the next evening; accepts invitation for tea, dated Wed. July 21; regrets he did not acknowledge their note sooner due to his absence & family affliction; presents them with a copy of "Brace Bridge Hall". [before 1830]
    Austin Kilbourn was a Litchfield Law School student in 1821.
  - Kirby, Miss (Folder 57)
    Accepts invitation of Miss Lewis for tea that evening.
  - Kirby, C.A., Miss (Folder 58)
    Note to Miss Lewis requesting a few wreaths of her hops flowers for young ladies at Mrs. Webb's.
  - Kirby, Catharine (Folder 59)
    Note to Mary Ann Lewis requesting a few geranium leaves and adds she hopes to see Mary Ann and her sister Louisa that evening. Dated Mon. Dec. 25.
  - Kirby, Helen (Folder 60)
    Note to Mary Ann Lewis inquiring about a dance.
    [before 1830]
  - Landon, Misses (Folder 61)
    Invitation for tea the next evening to the Misses Lewis. Dated Wed. June 24. [before 1830]
  - Landon, Misses (Folder 62)
    Invitation for tea that evening to Miss Lewis.
  - Landon, Misses (Folder 63)
    Invitation for tea the next evening to the Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Landon, Misses (Folder 64)
    Invitation to "pass the day tomorrow" to the Misses Lewis and Misses Cowles. Dated Fri. Jan. 29. [before 1830]
  - Landon, Miss (Folder 65)
    2 Invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Landon, Mr. and Mrs. (Folder 66)
    Invitation to the Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Lines, Miss (Folder 67)
    Miss Lines, Miss Lyman and MIss Lord accept invitation of Miss Lewis. They note that Mr. Miller and Mr. Green, who board with them, were not invited.
  - Litchfield Female Academy (Folder 68)
    The Young ladies at Miss Pierces invite Jane Lewis to spend the evening with them.
    Dated Mon. July 26. [before 1830]
  - Litchfield Female Seminary (Folder 69)
    The young ladies of the Litchfield Female Seminary invite Mr. and Mrs. Lewis and daughter to attend an exhibition at the Seminary on April 16th. [before 1839; Mr. Lewis died in 1839]
  - Livingston, Mr. (Folder 70)
    Regrets to Miss Lewis that he cannot accept her invitation for that evening due to a previous engagement.
  - Lord, Miss (Folder 71)
    2 invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis,3 invitations for tea to Miss Lewis, and 1 invitation to Miss Lewis and Miss Coles.
  - Lord, Misses (Folder 72)
    2 invitations to the Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Lord, Mr. and Mrs. (Folder 73)
    2 invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Lord, Mrs. (Folder 74)
    Invitation to Miss Jane Lewis. [before 1830]
  - Lord, Mrs. (Folder 75)
    Invitation to Miss M. Lewis
  - Lord, Mrs. (Folder 76)
    Mrs. & Miss Lord invitation for tea to the Misses Lewis. Dated Mon. Nov. 27. [before 1830]
  - Loring, Mr. (Folder 77)
    Regrets to the Misses Lewis that he has a previous engagement and cannot accept their invitation. [before 1830]
  - Lothrop, Miss (Folder 78)
    Accepts invitation of the Misses Lewis for that evening. [before 1830]
  - Maria (Folder 79)
    Invitation to Mary Ann Lewis to spend the afternoon.
  - Mary (Folder 80)
    Note to Mary.
  - McClean, J. G. (Folder 81)
    To Misses Lewis regrets that he cannot accept their invitation. [before 1830]
    James G. McLean was a Litchfield Law School student in 1822.
  - McElhenney, Mr. (Folder 82)
    Note to Misses Lewis that he accepts their invitation for the next evening. Dated Mon. Jan. 13. [before 1830]
    James McElhenny was a Litchfield Law School studetn in 1822.
  - Miller, Mr. (Folder 83)
    Note to the Misses Lewis that he accepts their invitation. [before 1830]
  - Peck, Mary (Folder 84)
    Note to the Misses Lewis to write in her album. [before 1830]
  - Peck, Miss (Folder 85)
  - Peck, Misses (Folder 86)
    2 invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. one is dated Tues. Aug. 23.
  - Pierce, Miss (Folder 87)
    Invitation for tea to Miss Lewis for that evening.
  - Reynolds, Mr., 1823 Jan 14 (Folder 88)
    From Mr. Reynolds & Mr. Adams to the Misses Lewis, accepting invitation to tea that evening. [before 1830]
    Walter Reynolds was a Litchfield Law School student in 1822-1823 and John Frink Adams was there in 1823.
  - Rogers, H., Mr. (Folder 89)
    Accepts invitation for tea of the Misses Lewis the next evening. Dated Tues. July 20. [before 1830]
  - Rogers, H. B., Mr. (Folder 90)
    Accepts invitation of the Misses Lewis for the next evening. Dated Tues. July 20. [before 1830]
    Henry Bromfield Rogers was a Litchfield Law School student in 1823.
  - Rutledge, Mr. (Folder 91)
    Note to the Misses Lewis,regrets he cannot accept their invitation. [before 1830]
    Benjamin Huger Rutledge was a Litchfield Law School student in 1817.
  - Seymour, Mr. and Mrs. O. (Folder 92)
    Invitation for tea to Miss Lewis.
  - Seymour, Misses (Folder 93)
    Note to the Misses Lewis regretting that the Misses Seymour cannot accept their invitation for tea that evening. Dated Thurs. Jan. 26. [before 1830]
  - Shaffer, Mr. (Folder 94)
    Accepts invitation of the Misses Lewis for tea that evening. [before 1830]
    Joseph L. Shaffer was a Litchfield Law School student in 1825.
  - Sheldon, Miss (Folder 95)
    2 invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. One dated Fri. Nov. 6th. [before 1830]
  - Sherman, Mr. (Folder 96)
    Accepts invitation of the Misses Lewis for that evening (Thursday) [before 1830]
    Elkanah C. Sherman was a Litchfield Law School student in 1825.
  - Smith, L., Mr. (Folder 97)
    To the Misses Lewis, accepts their invitation for tea that evening. [before 1830]
    Levi Smith was a Litchfield Law School student in 1824.
  - Smith, Mr. (Folder 98)
    Note to Miss Lewis that he regrets he cannot accept her invitation for tea that evening due to the arrival of friends. Dated July 14th.
  - Smith, Mr. (Folder 99)
    Note to the Misses Lewis that he accepts their invitation for tea. Dated Jan. 20 [26]?.
  - Smith, Miss (Folder 100)
    Regrets that she cannot accept the invitation of the Misses Lewis for that evening (Wednesday).
  - Snelling, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 101)
    Regret that they cannot accept the invitation of the Misses Lewis for that evening. Dated Wed. July 21. [before 1830]
  - Stewart, Mr (Folder 102)
    Regrets he is unable to accept the invitation of Miss Lewis because he is leaving town. May 11th.
  - Stewart, C.S. (Folder 103)
    Note to Miss Mary Ann Lewis regretting that [he] cannot visit her due to a trip to New York. Thursday Nov. 15th.
    Charles Samuel Stewart was a Litchfield Law School student in 1817.
  - Stiles, Mr. (Folder 104)
    Accepts invitation for tea of the Misses Lewis for the next evening. Dated Tuesday July 20th. [before 1830]
    Joseph Stiles was a Litchfield Law School student in 1817.
  - Stiles, Mr. and Mrs. (Folder 105)
    Accept invitation of Mr. and Mrs. Lewis for the next evening. Dated Sept. 15th.
  - Stiles, Joseph C (Folder 106)
    Joseph C. Stiles and Robert Maxwell, Managers, invite Miss Lewis to a tea party at Mr. Lewis' the next evening, Oct. 7th.
    Joseph C. Stiles and Robert Maxwell were Litchfield Law School studetn in 1817.
  - Stiles, Joseph [et al], 1818 Jan 21 (Folder 107)
    Invitation from Joseph Stiles, William H. Avenell, and William Greene to Miss Lewis to a Ball at the house of Mr. Phelps.
    Joseph Stiles, William H. Averell, and WIlliam Greene were at Litchfield Law School 1817-1818.
  - Taber, Mr. (Folder 108)
    Invitation to Miss M Lewis to the cotillion party at Mr. Cook's on Thursday. Wednesday morning.
    Wiliam J. Tabor was a Litchfield Law School student 1813-.
  - Tallmadge, Miss, 1819 Dec 28 (Folder 109)
    Invitation for tea the next evening to the Misses Lewis.
  - Tallmadge, Miss and Tallmadge, George Washington, 1819 Jul 12 (Folder 110)
    Accept the invitation of Miss Lewis for that evening.
  - Tallmadge, Miss, 1820 Nov 20 (Folder 111)
    Invitation for tea for the next evening to the Misses Lewis.
  - Tallmadge, Maria (Folder 112)
    Note to Marian Lewis asking to borrow mourning bonnets.
  - Tallmadge, Miss (Folder 113)
    Accepts Miss Lewis' invitation for that evening. September 25.
  - Tallmadge, Miss (Folder 114)
    Invitation for tea the next evening to Miss Lewis. Dated Feb. 19th.
  - Tallmadge, Mr. (Folder 115)
    Regrets he cannot accept the invitation of the Misses Lewis for that evening due to a trip to Albany. January 14th. [before 1830]
  - Taylor, S., Miss (Folder 116)
    Invitation to Jane Lewis for that evening. Friday morning. [before1830]
  - T., H. (Folder 117)
    Note to Mary Ann Lewis regarding a sleigh ride that was postponed by Mr. Gould due to a storm.
  - VanderHeyden, S (Folder 118)
    Invitation for that evening at Miss Pierce's to Jane Lewis. [before 1830]
  - W., E. (Folder 119)
    Note to Jane R. Lewis about some notes and being in Canada. [before 1830]
  - Wadsworth, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 120)
    Invitation for tea that evening to the Misses Lewis. Thursday morning. [before 1830]
  - Webb, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 121)
  - Webb, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 122)
    Invitation for tea that evening to Miss M. & L. Lewis. Thursday morning Sept. 21st. [before 1830]
  - Webb, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 123)
    Invitation for tea that evening to the Misses Lewis. Nov. 25th. [before 1830]
  - Webb, Mr. & Mrs. (Folder 124)
    Invitation for tea to Maryann Lewis for Wed. Sept. 1st. Dated August 31st.
  - Webb, Mr. (Folder 125)
    Invitation to Maryann Lewis for the next evening. Dated April 4th.
  - Whiting, Mr. (Folder 126)
    To the Misses Lewis, accepts invitation for tea that evening. Wednesday July 21. [before 1830]
    John Whiting was a Litchfield Law School student in 1823.
  - Wilson, Mr. (Folder 127)
    Requests Miss Lewis write a few lines in his album. Friday noon.
  - Wolcott, E., Miss (Folder 128)
    Requests the company of Jane Lewis that evening. Friday morning. [before 1830]
  - Wolcott, M. G. (Folder 129)
    Invitation for tea for that evening to Mary Ann Lewis. Wednesday morning.
  - Wolcott, Hannah Huntington (Folder 130)
    Invitation for tea and to meet Miss Terry that evening to Mary Ann Lewis and her sisters. [before 1830]
  - Wolcott, Hannah Huntington (Folder 131)
    To Mary Ann Lewis a note that she will not be able to call on her due to her sister Mary Ann and brother Frederick leaving town. Saturday.
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 132)
    3 invitations for tea to the Misses Lewis. Dated Jan. 22nd; Sept. 17th; Dec.22nd. [before 1830]
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 133)
    Note to the Misses Lewis accepting their invitation for that evening. Tuesday morning.
    [befoe 1830]
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 134)
    Accept invitation of Miss Lewis for that evening. Thursday morning
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 135)
    The Miss Wolcott & Miss Cooke invite the Misses Lewis for tea on Wed. Dated July 6th. [before 1830]
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 136)
    Invitation for tea to Miss Lewis. Dated Feb. 15th.
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 137)
    Invitation for Friday evening to Mary Ann Lewis. Wednesday June 19th.
  - Wolcott, Misses (Folder 138)
    Invitation to Mr. & Mrs. Lewis for the next evening. Dated Sept. 15th.
  - Wolcott, Mr. & Mrs. Oliver S (Folder 139)
    Invitation for tea to the Misses Lewis. Dated January 20th. [before 1830]
  - Wolcott, Mr. & Mrs. Oliver S (Folder 140)
    Invitation for tea to the Misses Lewis. Dated April 25th. [before 1830]
  - Wolcott, Mr. & Mrs. Oliver S (Folder 141)
    Invitation for tea on Wed. Nov. 24th to the Misses Lewis. Dated Nov. 22. [before 1830]
- Miscellaneous, 1811-1895
  This series includes miscellaneous correspondence, essays, newspaper clippings, and other items. Due to the dates after the death of Mary Ann Lewis in 1884, a few would have belonged to Mary Lewis Phelps.
  - Barney, Mr. & Mrs. Newcomb Cushman, 1895 May 28 (Folder 1)
    Wedding invitation for their daughter Elizabeth Cynthia Barney to Dr. John Laidlaw Buel. Also newspaper clipping about the wedding.
  - Byron, Lord (Folder 2)
    Handwritten copy of "Darkness" by Lord Byron. Dated 1819.
  - Cutler, George Younglove (Folder 3)
    Handwritten poem to Litchfield Female Academy student. First line "Let's fill our cups to beauty bright" Mentions LFA students by last name.
    George Younglove Cutler was a Litchfiled Law School studetn in 1819.
  - Deming, Emma, 1851 (Folder 4)
    To Miss M.L.P. [Mary Lewis Phelps] a small piece of paper with an alphabetic code.
  - Goodwin, Henry W (Folder 5)
    Business card for Henry W. Goodwin, importer and dealer in china, glass and earthen war, etc. in Hartford, Conn.
  - "Hymn to the Virgin" (Folder 6)
    Handwritten poem sent to Miss Mary Ann Lewis, Litchfield.
  - "The immortality of the soul" (Folder 7)
    Handwritten essay.
  - Julia, Cousin (Folder 8)
    Letter addressed to M.A.L. to "My dear cousins" with family news.